As the entire world teetered on the brink of global destruction, there arose a man unlike any other...a man who
personified truth and justice and all the hopes of mankind. They called him Captain America.
Captain America is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Albert Pyun.
During World War II, a brave, patriotic American Soldier undergoes
experiments to become a new supersoldier, "Captain America".
Racing to Germany to sabotage the rockets of Nazi baddie "Red
Skull", Captain America winds up frozen until the 1990s.
He reawakens to find that the Red Skull has changed identities and is now
planning to kidnap the President of the United States.
Steve Rogers / Captain America, played by Matt Salinger.
Tom Kimball, played by Ronny Cox.
Sam Kolawetz, played by Ned Beatty.
General Fleming, played by Darren McGavin.
Lt. Colonel Louis, played by Michael Nouri.
The Red Skull / Army Doctor, played by Scott Paulin.
Captain America is a 1990 American superhero film based on
the Marvel Comics superhero of the same name.
It is directed by Albert Pyun and written by Stephen
Tolkin, from a story by Tolkin and Larry Block.
It stars Matt Salinger in the title role and Scott Paulin as his nemesis the Red Skull, with Ronny
Cox, Ned Beatty, Darren McGavin, Francesca Neri, Michael Nouri and Melinda Dillon.
The film produced by Menahem Golan for the
now-defunct 21st Century Film Corporation.
While the film takes several liberties with the comic's storyline, it features Steve Rogers becoming Captain America during World War II to battle the Red Skull, being
frozen in ice, and subsequently being revived to save the President of the United States from a crime family that dislikes his environmentalist policies.
While the film received a theatrical release internationally, it
was released direct-to-video in the United States.
It received generally unfavorable reviews from critics,
though it has since developed a cult following.
The film explores themes of martial arts, washington dc,
usa, superhero, wretch, based on comic.
The tone is thought_provoking.